Guide to the Records of The New York Institute for the Humanities RG.37.4
New York University Archives
- Series III: Audio Recordings, 67170
  - Subseries A: Cassette Tapes, 1974-2005; 67171
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 6a, 15-Jun-95; cuid3975; 67307 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 6b, 15-Jun-95; cuid3976; 67306 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 7, 15-Jun-95; cuid3977; 67305 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 8a, 15-Jun-95; cuid3978; 67304 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 8b, 15-Jun-95; cuid3979; 67303 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 9, 16-Jun; cuid3980; 67302 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 1 copy, 14-Jun-95; cuid3981; 67301 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273766
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 2 copy, 14-Jun-95; cuid3982; 67300 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 3 copy, 14-Jun-95; cuid3983; 67299 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 4 copy, 14-Jun-95; cuid3984; 67298 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 5a copy, 15-Jun-95; cuid3985; 67297 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 5b copy, 15-Jun-95; cuid3986; 67296 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 6a copy, 15-Jun-95; cuid3987; 67295 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 6b copy, 15-Jun-95; cuid3988; 67294 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 7 copy, 15-Jun-95; cuid3989; 67293 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 8a copy, 15-Jun-95; cuid3990; 67292 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 8b copy, 15-Jun-95; cuid3991; 67291 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 1, 14-Jun-95; cuid3992; 67290 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273774
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 1 copy, cuid3993; 67289 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 2, 14-Jun-95; cuid3994; 67288 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 3, 14-Jun-95; cuid3995; 67287 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 4, 14-Jun-95; cuid3996; 67286 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 5a, 15-Jun-95; cuid3997; 67285 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 5b, 15-Jun-95; cuid3998; 67284 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 6b, 15-Jun-95; cuid3999; 67283 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 7, 15-Jun-95; cuid4000; 67282 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 8a, 15-Jun-95; cuid4001; 67281 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Conference on Cities in North America Tape 8b, 15-Jun-95; cuid4002; 67280 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Michael Lind, "What is the Society for a Social Democratic Project?", 6-Oct-95; cuid4003; 67279 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277817
    - Eric Hobsbawm, "Inventing Your Own History", 13-Oct-95; cuid4004; 67278 (Box 61, Folder 2, Box Digitized Access Files, File rg37.4_cuid4004)
    - Eric Hobsbawm, 13-Oct-95; cuid4005; 67277 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Alex Stille, "Mafia and Politics in Contemporary Italy", 20-Oct-95; cuid4006; 67276 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - James Atlas, "On Writing the Biography of Saul Bellow", 27-Oct-95; cuid4007; 67275 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Robert Wright, "Family Values in the Genes", 10-Nov-95; cuid4008; 67274 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Todd Gitlin, "America's Culture Wars", 3-Nov-95; cuid4009; 67273 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Jocelyn Carlson Baltzell, 17-Nov-95; cuid4010; 67272 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Jocelyn Carlson Baltzell, 1-Dec-95; cuid4011; 67271 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Jocelyn Carlson Baltzell, 8-Dec-95; cuid4012; 67270 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Sherry Turkle, 16-Feb-96; cuid4013; 67269 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Adrian Piper, 9-Mar-96; cuid216; 67268 (Box 61, Folder 12, Box Access 14)
    - Deutsches Haus, 25-Oct-96; cuid4014; 67267 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Vincent Crapanzano, "Conceptualizing Social and Cultural Reality Non-Textual Interpretation", 6-Dec-96; cuid4015; 67266 (Box 62, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277825
    - Cinema Conference, nd; cuid4016; 67265 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Cinema Conference, nd; cuid4017; 67264 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Cinema Conference, nd; cuid4018; 67263 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Gary Wills, "The Life of St. Augustine", 26-Sep-97; cuid4019; 67262 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277833
    - Richard Howard, "Ascending the Monuments: The Poetry of Homage", 3-Oct-97; cuid4020; 67261 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Jane Kramer, "On the Washington State Militia", 10-Oct-97; cuid4021; 67260 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Elizabeth Holtzman, "On the Upcoming Mayoral Election", 17-Oct-97; cuid4022; 67259 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - David Garland, "The New Strategies of Crime Control: Sources and Contradictions", 24-Oct-97; cuid4023; 67258 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Rosalind Krauss, "Painting Without a Past: Part II of Poetry Without a Past", 31-Oct-97; cuid4024; 67257 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Jerome Bruner, Frances Fitzgerald and Aryeh Neier - The NYIH at 20, 7-Nov-97; cuid4025; 67256 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - James Chace, "Dean Acheson: Faustian Bargains and the End of the Cold War", 14-Nov-97; cuid4026; 67255 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Andre Aciman, "Water Cities: Writing from Memory", 21-Nov-97; cuid4027; 67254 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Stanley Crouch, "Blues for Tomorrow", 6-Feb-98; cuid4028; 67253 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277841
    - Oliver Sacks, "The End of Science", 13-Feb-98; cuid4029; 67252 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Brian Urquhart, "If There is a World Community, Who is the Sheriff?", 20-Feb-98; cuid4030; 67251 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Nancy Vickers, "Dante and the Language of Television", 27-Feb-98; cuid4031; 67250 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Elaine Showalter, "Hysterical Epidemics", 6-Mar-98; cuid4032; 67249 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Tamar Jacoby, "Integration: The Wrong Means to the Right End", 13-Mar-98; cuid4033; 67248 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Stanley Cavell, 27-Mar-98; cuid4034; 67247 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Arnold Rampersad, "The Search for the Real Jackie Robinson", 3-Apr-98; cuid4035; 67246 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Fareed Zakaria, "Illiberal Democracy", 17-Apr-98; cuid4036; 67245 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Barbara Ehrenreich, "Public Ecstasy", 24-Apr-98; cuid4037; 67244 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Mark Danner, "American Intervention, Haitian and Bosnian Crisis", 1-May-98; cuid4038; 67243 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - David Remnick, "Race, Hype, and Heavyweight Championship", 25-Sep-98; cuid4039; 67242 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277858
    - Edward Said, "Opera's Problems", 2-Oct-98; cuid4040; 67241 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Jessica Benjamin, "Freud and Femininity", 9-Oct-98; cuid4041; 67240 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Catherine Stimpson, "Gertrude and Her Politics", 16-Oct-98; cuid4042; 67239 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Hal Foster, "The State of Criticism", 23-Oct-98; cuid4043; 67238 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Jane Gallop, "Resisting Reasonableness: Consensual Amorous Relations, Pedagogy, and Conflict of Interest", 30-Oct-98; cuid4044; 67237 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Tom Bishop, "Unblocking Memory for a Memoir", 6-Nov-98; cuid4045; 67236 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Jerome Bruner, "Inventing Infancy", 20-Nov-98; cuid4046; 67235 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Shashi Tharoor, "On India", 11-Dec-98; cuid4047; 67234 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Linda Nochlin, "The Modernity of Mary Cassatt", 5-Feb-99; cuid4048; 67233 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Rosalind Krauss, "On Jackson Pollock", 5-Feb-99; cuid4049; 67232 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Lawrence Weschler, "The Exile and Calamitous Return of Breyten Breytenbach", 9-Feb-99; cuid4050; 67231 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Ari Zolberg, "Immigration and the Future of the Nation State", 26-Feb-99; cuid4051; 67230 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - David Rieff, "Humanitariansim and the Human Rights: Convergence and Contradictions", 5-Mar-99; cuid4052; 67229 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277866
    - Morris Dickstein, "Roots of the Counter Culture", 12-Mar-99; cuid4053; 67228 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Jerry Siegel, "What is Bourgeois Individualism", 9-Apr-99; cuid4054; 67227 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Leonard Barkan, "A Circle of Shades", 16-Apr-99; cuid4055; 67226 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Leonard Barkan, "A Circle of Shades", 16-Apr-99; cuid4056; 67225 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Robert Paxton, "Vichy in the Courtoom: The Trial of Maurice Papon", 30-Apr-99; cuid4057; 67224 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Particia Williams, "The Emperor's New Clothes", 30-Apr-99; cuid4058; 67223 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Arnold Steinhardt, "The Courtesan and the Violinist", 24-Sep-99; cuid4059; 67222 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277874
    - Mary Poovey, "NYIH and Interdisciplinarity at NYU", 1-Oct-99; cuid4060; 67221 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Urvashi Vaid, "Toward a New Coalition in the Gay and Lesbian Movement", 15-Oct-99; cuid4061; 67220 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Terry Riley, "Rethinking Critical Space: Redesigning the Museum of Modern Art", 22-Oct-99; cuid4062; 67219 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Tony Hiss, "The View from Alger's Window", 29-Oct-99; cuid4063; 67218 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - David Denby, "James Agee in 1945: Movies and Criticism Now", 5-Nov-99; cuid4064; 67217 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Troy Duster, "The Racialization of Politics and the Politicization of Race", 12-Nov-99; cuid4065; 67216 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Stephen Jay Gould, "Questioning the Millennium", 19-Nov-99; cuid4066; 67215 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Charles Halpern, "On Y2K: Reflections at the End of the Millennium", 3-Dec-99; cuid4067; 67214 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Joan Acocella, "Editing Nijinsky's Diary", 10-Dec-99; cuid4068; 67213 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Nicholas Lemann, "Meritocracy in America", 4-Feb-00; cuid4069; 67212 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Richard Sennett, "Work and Its Discontents", 11-Feb-00; cuid4070; 67211 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Peter Singer, "The Sanctity of Life", 18-Feb-00; cuid4071; 67210 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Rayna Rapp, "Gender and Genomes: An Anthropological Perspective on How New Genetic Knowledge Gets Made and What Happens to It", 3-Mar-00; cuid4072; 67209 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Jonathan Schell, "On the Presidential Primaries", 10-Mar-00; cuid4073; 67208 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Mary Ellen Burns, "From Dot-dash to Dot-com: Prespectives on the Past and future of the Internet", 24-Mar-00; cuid4074; 67207 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Komar and Melamid, "Art and Collaboration: Other Artists, Other Species", 31-Mar-00; cuid4075; 67206 (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Lydia Davies, On Translating Proust, 7-Apr-00; cuid4076; 67205 (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Betty Fussell, "The Meaning of the Kitchen", 14-Apr-00; cuid4077; 67204 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Michael Cunningham, "Virginia Woolf and Chaos Theory: Time, Synchronicity, and Other Impossible Problems in the Novel", 22-Sep-00; cuid4078; 67203 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042277882
      Access copy available on CD: Access 11:52
    - Doug Guthrie, "The End of History? Political, Economic and Social Change in China", 29-Sep-00; cuid4079; 67202 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Jessica Yu, "A Cast of Trillions: The Art of Henry Darger", 6-Oct-00; cuid4080; 67201 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:54
    - Daniel Pipes, "The Current Crisis in the Middle East", 13-Oct-00; cuid4081; 67200 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:55
    - Breyten Breytenbach, "Notes from the Middle World", 20-Oct-00; cuid4082; 67199 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:56
    - Colm Toibin, "The Legacy of Coole: Lade Gregory, Sir William Gregory, and the Creation of an Irish National Identity", 27-Oct-00; cuid4083; 67198 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:57
    - Philip Gourevitch, "Black and White and Gray Over: Some Thoughts on the Problems and Politics of Journalistic Evenhandedness", 3-Nov-00; cuid4084; 67197 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:58
    - Robert Krulwich, "Panic in the News Room", 10-Nov-00; cuid4085; 67196 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:59
    - Fred Siegel, "Mayors and Morality: Daley and Lindsay, Then and Now", 17-Nov-00; cuid4086; 67195 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:60
    - Edward Rothstein, " Music and Masterpieces: Why Audiences Love the 19th Century", 1-Dec-00; cuid4087; 67194 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:1
    - Bruce Chilton, "The Rabbi's Revenge, The Story of Jesus", 8-Dec-00; cuid4088; 67193 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:2
    - Noelle Oxenhandler, "The Eros of Parenthood: Explorations in Light and Dark", 9-Jan-01; cuid4089; 67192 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:3
    - Mark Salzman, "Why I Love the Bach Cello Suites: A Talk and Performance", 2-Feb-01; cuid4090; 67191 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:4
    - Robert Hollander, "Justice and Poetry: Dante's Book of the Dead", 16-Feb-01; cuid4091; 67190 (Box 68, Folder 14)
      Access copy available: ACCESS 12:5
    - Kenneth Frampton, "Megaform as Urban Landscape", 23-Feb-01; cuid4092; 67189 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:6
    - Roald Hoffmann, "The Royal Purple and the Biblical Blue: A Story of Religion, Protochemistry and Politics", 2-Mar-01; cuid4093; 67188 (Box 68, Folder 16)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:7
    - Michael Wood, "The Interpretation of Oracles: The Irrational and Its Reasons", 9-Mar-01; cuid4094; 67187 (Box 68, Folder 17)
      Access copy available: ACCESS 12:8
    - Herbert Leibowitz, "Parnassus at 25: Some Night Thoughts of an Editor on Poets, Poetry and the Decline of Literary Language", 23-Mar-01; cuid4095; 67186 (Box 68, Folder 18)
      Access copy available: ACCESS 12:9
    - Elizabeth Holtzman, "The Election and the Court", 30-Mar-01; cuid4096; 67185 (Box 68, Folder 19)
      Access copy available: ACCESS 12:10
    - Martin Kace, "Coma and After", 6-Apr-01; cuid4097; 67184 (Box 68, Folder 20)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:11
    - Claudia Roth Pierpont, "On Lincoln Kirstein", 20-Apr-01; cuid4098; 67183 (Box 68, Folder 21)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 12:12
    - Francine du Plessix Gray, "Loving and Hating Simone Weil", 27-Apr-01; cuid4099; 67182 (Box 68, Folder 22)
      Access copy available: ACCESS 12:13
    - Post-Lecture Lunch Discussion on Music Theory and Research with Steve Reich., 23-Apr-82; cuid4100; 67181; 1 sound cassettes (Box 69, Folder 1, Box Access 5, Item 25)
      barcode#:31142042277890
      This recording appears to be of conversation over lunch after a lecture. Steve Reich and others discuss music theory and his research for the lecture he has already given. (See related materials note)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 5:25.
      Related materials
      Steve Reich gave a lecture shortly before this lunch discussion. It is available as part of this collection (Discussion with Steve Reich: A "New American Music Series" Gallatin Lecture, Box 75, Folder 9).
      New York Institute for the Humanities; Reich, Steve, 1936-
    - War in Bosnia. A Discussion with David Rieff, 25-Feb-93; cuid4101; 67180; 1 sound cassettes Approx. 90 minutes; Business card of Jocelyn Eklof Carlson, New York Institute for the Humanities found in case with cassette. (Box 69, Folder 2, Box Access 5, Item 26, Item 27)
      Access copy available on 2 CDS: ACCESS 5:26 & ACCESS 5:27.
      David Rieff, just returned from Bosnia, discusses the war conditions and experience of the Bosnian people. A little less than half of the recording is Rieff giving his talk, then it is opened up to questions. While there is some back and forth/conversation from the small group, this Q&A is still predominantly Rieff giving very detailed answers to questions.
      New York Institute for the Humanities; Yugoslav War, 1991-1995 -- Personal narratives, Bosnian; Sarajevo (Bosnia and Hercegovina); War stories, Bosnian; United Nations. Security Council.; Rieff, David
    - Symposium on Science and the Humanities with Denis Donoghue and Gerald Holton, 31-Oct-86; cuid4102; 67179; 1 sound cassettes Approximately 73 minutes (Box 69, Folder 3, Box Access 5, Item 28)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 5:28
      Mallinckrodt Research Professor of Physics at Harvard University, Gerald Holton and Henry James Chair of English and American Letters at New York University, Denis Donoghue present brief lectures on the measures of progress in their varying fields. The program was designed as a way of bringing prominent members of the science and humanities communities together in a single venue and treat the lectures as a means of conversation between the two which are sometimes seen as oppositional to each other. The program is moderated by a man only once referred to by name as "Will." Holton and Donoghue speak for about 20 minutes each. The remaining half-hour is dedicated to Q&A with them both.
      Literary criticism (New York, N.Y.); Literature/literary criticism; Humanities; Science and the humanities; Physics -- Study and teaching -- United States; New York Institute for the Humanities; Donoghue, Denis; Holton, Gerald James
    - Daniel Bell and Susan Sontag Tape 1, 12-Dec-94; cuid4103; 67178 (Box 69, Folder 4)
      Access copy available on 2 CDs: ACCESS 11:10 and ACCESS 11:11
    - Daniel Bell and Susan Sontag Tape 2, 12-Dec-94; cuid4104; 67177 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 11:12
    - Symposium on Conservatism, Liberalism, and Intellectualism with Paul Starr and Robert L. Heilbroner, 8-Feb-95; cuid4105; 67176; 1 sound cassettes Approximately 82 minutes (Box 69, Folder 6, Box Access 5, Item 29, Item 30)
      Access copy available on two CDs: ACCESS 5:29 & ACCESS 5:30.
      Pulitzer Prize-winning professor of sociology and public affairs at Princeton University Paul Starr and American economist, historian of economic thought and author of The Worldly Philosophers: The Lives, Times and Ideas of the Great Economic Thinkers (1953), Robert L. Heilbroner give lectures on liberalism, conservatism and intellectualism. Starr speaks for about 30 minutes on the shift of conservative disdain of outright Communisim and Socialism to basic democratic liberalism as being seen as a threat to American ideals. Heilbroner speaks for only about 10 minutes on intellectualism and it's relationships to both liberalism and conservativism. The remaining 30-40 minutes are dedicated to Q&A and conversation between the two. The program is moderated by a man referred to only once as "Michael."
      Conservatism; Liberalism; Radicalism; Socialism.; New York (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Health care reform; Welfare rights movement; Contemporary politics; Heilbroner, Robert L.; Starr, Paul, 1949-
    - Roundtable on Commercial Culture and the Working Class in 19th Century Paris, 3-Oct-86; cuid4106; 67175; 1 sound cassettes Approximately 73 minutes (Box 69, Folder 7, Box Access 5, Item 31)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 5:31.
      Round table conversation of unnamed participants, on the working class and its relationship with commercial culture and art in the 19th century. A good portion of the conversation revolves around T.J. Clark's book, The Painting of Modern Life: Paris in the Art of Manet and His Followers. The formal conversation ends about 5 minutes before the recording and that time is filled with layered banter between the participants.
      Paris (France) |x Intellectual life |y 19th century.; Realism in art; Impressionist (style); realism (artistic form of expression); Paris (France) -- History.; Paris (France); bourgeoisie; Working class; Artists.; Art.; Impressionism (Art); Manet, Édouard, 1832-1883; Clark, T. J. (Timothy J.)
    - The Operas of Philip Glass, 30-Apr-82; cuid4107; 67174; 1 sound cassettes (Box 69, Folder 8, Box Access 5, Item 32)
      Philip Glass discusses his work as a "composer who writes operas" and his incorporation of historical personages such as Albert Einstein, Mahatma Gandhi, and Eadweard Muybridge.
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 5:32
      Opera.; Gandhi, Mahatma, 1869-1948; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Muybridge, Eadweard, 1830-1904; Glass, Philip
    - Round Table Discussion on Architecture of Urban Cultural Centers, 17-Apr-79; cuid4108; 67173; 1 sound cassettes Approximately 1 hour, 20 minutes (Box 69, Folder 9, Box Access 5, Item 33, Item 34)
      Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 5:33 & ACCESS :5:34
      Philip Johnson (architect of the New York State Theater and Lincoln Center), Richard Gilman (drama critic), Ellen Stewart (founder/director of LaMama tTheater) and Paul Goldberger (New York Times architecture critic) discuss the relationship between cultural spaces, the various "publics" that use them, and the art and cultural materials/identities that are produced as a result of them. Speakers present a brief statement and then engage in discussion with each other and the audience.
      La Mama Theatre; Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts; Ellen Stewart Theatre (Organization: New York, N.Y.); Cultural centers; performing arts centers; Culture.; Goldberger, Paul; Stewart, Ellen, 1919-2011; Johnson, Philip, 1906-2005; Gilman, Richard, 1923-2006
    - Forum on Public Art in the City, 20-Nov-78; cuid4109; 67172; 1 sound cassettes (Box 69, Folder 10, Box Access 5, Item 35, Item 36)
      Access copy available on 2 CDs: ACCESS 3:35 & ACCESS 3:36
      Participants include sculptor Robert Murray, painter Janet Henry, and architect Kenneth Frampton.
    - Creating the book "Aftermath: World Trade Center Archive", Lecture by photographer Joel Meyerowitz, 13-May-2002; cuid4110; 180481; 2 sound cassettes Approx. 100 minutes. (Box 72, Folder 2, Box Access 7, Item 19, Item 20, Item 21)
      Access copy available on three CDs: ACCESS 7:19, ACCESS 7:20, and ACCESS 7:21.
      After lengthy introductions by NYU President John Sexton and Lawrence Weschler, the lecture begins about 18 minutes into the recording. Photographer, Joel Meyerowitz discusses his work creating a photographic archive of the aftermath of the September 11, 2001 attacks on the World Trade Center which culminated with his book, Aftermath: World Trade Center Archive.
      September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001.; Photographers -- United States.; Joel Meyerowitz book; Photography; Photographs.; Weschler, Lawrence; Sexton, John Edward, 1942-; Meyerowitz, Joel, 1938-
    - Episodes of This American Life and All Things Considered (Tony Grafton Discusses Kircher symposium), May 22, 2002; cuid4111; 180484; 1 sound cassettes (Box 72, Folder 4, Box Access 7, Item 22, Item 23)
      The Kircher symposium which Grafton discusses was recorded and is available as part of this collection (The Life and Work of Athanasius Kircher, Box 72, Folder 5).